{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Maximum size of foreign DNA that can be inserted into a replacement vector is", "opta": "25-30 kb", "optb": "18-20 kb", "optc": "20-25 kb", "optd": "40-50 kb", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not true about phagemid?", "opta": "Contain functional origin of replication of the plasmid and \u03bb phage", "optb": "May be propagated as a plasmid or as phage in appropriate strain", "optc": "Contain \u03bb att site", "optd": "Can only be propagated as phage", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "pBR 322 has/have which of the following selection marker(s)?", "opta": "Ampr", "optb": "Tetr", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Kanr", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A plasmid can be considered as a suitable cloning vector if", "opta": "it can be readily isolated from the cells", "optb": "it possesses a single restriction site for one or more restriction enzymes", "optc": "insertion of foreign DNA does not alter its replication properties", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Difference between \u03bb gt 10 and \u03bb gt 11 vectors is that", "opta": "\u03bb gt 11 is an expression vector", "optb": "\u03bb gt 10 is an expression vector", "optc": "\u03bb gt 10 is a replacement vector", "optd": "\u03bb gt 11 is a replacement vector", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\u03bb ZAP vector is an example of", "opta": "phage", "optb": "phagemid", "optc": "cosmid", "optd": "plasmid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "\u03bb gt 10 and \u03bb gt 11 vectors can propagate cloned fragments up to", "opta": "6-7 kb", "optb": "1-2 kb", "optc": "40-44 kb", "optd": "20-23 kb", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select the wrong statement about plasmids?", "opta": "It is extrachromosomal", "optb": "It is double stranded", "optc": "Its replication depends upon host cell", "optd": "It is closed and circular DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Stuffer is", "opta": "the right arm of the vector DNA", "optb": "the left arm of the vector DNA", "optc": "central fragment of the vector DNA", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Conjugative plasmids", "opta": "exhibit antibiotic resistance", "optb": "do not exhibit antibiotic resistance", "optc": "carry transfer genes called the tra genes", "optd": "do not carry transfer genes", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plasmid incompatibility is", "opta": "inability of a plasmid to grow in the host", "optb": "inability of two different plasmids to coexist in the same host cell in the absence of selection pressure.", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "P1 cloning vector allow cloning of DNA of the length of", "opta": "100 kbp", "optb": "50 kbp", "optc": "20 kbp", "optd": "10 kbp", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Charon 34 and Charon 35 can clone DNA upto", "opta": "1-2 kb", "optb": "6-7 kb", "optc": "9-20 kb", "optd": "30-35 kb", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Charon vectors are different from EMBL vectors because", "opta": "they have more extensive range of restriction targets with in their polylinkers.", "optb": "physical separation of lambda arm from central fragment is required", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "physical separation of lambda arm from central fragment is not required", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "P1 cloning vector is the example of", "opta": "plasmid", "optb": "cosmid", "optc": "bacteriophage", "optd": "phagemid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cos site of the cosmids", "opta": "consists of 12 bases", "optb": "helps whole genome in circularization and ligation", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "contains cleavage site", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "M 13 is an example of", "opta": "filamentous phage", "optb": "single stranded DNA vector", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "plasmid", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phagemid vectors are", "opta": "combination of plasmid and phage \u03bb", "optb": "combination of phages and cosmid", "optc": "phages carrying properties of plasmids", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Single stranded vectors are useful", "opta": "for sequencing of cloned DNA", "optb": "for oligonucleotide directed mutagenesis", "optc": "for probe preparation", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Inserted DNA in \u03bb gt 11 can be expressed as", "opta": "\u03b2-galactosidase fused protein", "optb": "free protein in the cytoplasm", "optc": "free protein that is secreted out", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "EMBL 3 and EMBL 4 are replacement vectors, which can clone DNA up to", "opta": "6-7 kb", "optb": "15-25 kb", "optc": "40-44 kb", "optd": "1-2 kb", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Size of the DNA that can be packaged into a \u03bb phage is", "opta": "50 kb", "optb": "35-53 kb", "optc": "40-50 kb", "optd": "any size", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Charon 34 and Charon 35 are the examples of", "opta": "plasmid vector", "optb": "cosmid vector", "optc": "phage vector", "optd": "phagemid vector", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cosmid vectors are used for", "opta": "cloning small fragments of DNA", "optb": "cloning large fragments of DNA", "optc": "cloning prokaryotic DNA only", "optd": "cloning eukaryotic DNA only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plasmids which are maintained as limited number of copies per cell are known as", "opta": "stringent plasmids", "optb": "relaxed plasmids", "optc": "cryptic plasmids", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cryptic plasmids", "opta": "do not exhibit any phenotypic trait", "optb": "exhibit many phenotypic traits", "optc": "exhibit one phenotypic traits", "optd": "exhibit antibiotic resistance", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Phagemid consist of", "opta": "plasmid vector carrying \u03bb phage's cos site", "optb": "plasmid vector carrying \u03bb attachment (\u03bb att) site", "optc": "plasmid vector carrying origin of replication of \u03bb phage only", "optd": "plasmid vector carrying origin of replication of plasmid only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Maximum size of foreign DNA that can be inserted into an insertion vector is", "opta": "35 kb", "optb": "18 kb", "optc": "50 kb", "optd": "27 kb", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Plasmids which are maintained as multiple copy number per cell are known as", "opta": "stringent plasmids", "optb": "relaxed plasmids", "optc": "cryptic plasmids", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cosmid vectors are", "opta": "plasmids that contain fragment of \u03bb DNA including the cos site", "optb": "phages that lack cos site", "optc": "plasmids that have no selection marker", "optd": "cryptic plasmids", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cosmids lack", "opta": "genes coding for viral proteins", "optb": "origin of replication", "optc": "marker genes coding for replication", "optd": "cleavage site for the insertion of foreign DNA", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}